JOSHUA AVERETT SOFTWARE ENGINEER

5435 E BOSTON ST MESA, AZ 85205 (480) 309-3671 joshua.averett@gmail.com https://github.com/javerett

Software development professional offering 5+ years of industry experience in system architecture development with a Bachelor's of Engineering degree in Computer Engineering from Arizona State University. An Employee of the Month Award winner with a strong attention to detail, excellent critical thinking skills, and the crucial ability to function well in a team setting. Experienced in the full project lifecycle, from initial design and implementation to deployment and maintenance.

EXPERIENCE

Head Solidity Developer

Panarka Blockchain Labs | Remote — January 2021 - PRESENT

- Contributed as one of the principal backend programmers

- Developed Solidity smart contracts for the Penguin Party network
- Tasked with building DAO in Ethereum to handle token voting
- Performed regression and system level testing to verify software quality and function prior to release
- Collaborated with other developers and performance engineers to enhance supportability and identify performance bottlenecks
- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products

Lead RF Engineer

CTS Inc | Phoenix, AZ — September 2019 - PRESENT

- Developed an intelligently scaling turnkey web app for project management with Haskell/Elm system, reducing manual data entry, saving hundreds of personnel hours monthly
- Developed a C#/LINQ based desktop app that functioned as a design automation system, saving hours per project.
- Employee of the Month

Head Fullstack Developer

CircuitBloom | Remote – July 2014 - September 2019

- Reviewed code to validate structures, assess security and verify browser, device and operating system capabilities
- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement
- Took concepts and produced mockups and prototypes to develop, and enhance user experiences and improve site interactions
- Streamlined high server traffic resource configuration and allocation
- Successfully installed Linux Servers and virtualized environments using Docker, Hyper-V, and Amazon Web services

Maintenance Tech

Sherer Engineering Inc | Mesa, AZ — July 2013 - July 2014

- Repaired semiconductor equipment; Implanters, cone replacements, chillers and turbopumps
- CAD/CAM using Autodesk Inventor
- Systems Administration

SKILLS

Languages:

Solidity, Haskell, Nix, Elm, C#, C, C++, JavaScript, LINQ, PHP, HTML/CSS, (& More)

Database Management:

SQL Server, Postgres, Mongo

Systems: Linux, Windows/ Windows Server, Mac OS X

STRENGTHS

Technical:

- Program Design
- Blockchain Engineering
- Testing and Debugging
- API Design Knowledge
- Data Management
- Certified for ADRF
 Cellphone System Design

Practical:

- Ability to prioritize
- Communication
- Critical thinking
- Determination
- Efficiency
- Innovation

EDUCATION

Arizona State University

Bachelors of Engineering Computer Engineering August 2012 - May 2016